&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：现在，我们终于可以讨论模块模式了。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Now, we finally get to talk about the module pattern.
我们通过对词汇范围的坚实理解建立了自己。
We've built ourselves up through a solid understanding of lexical scope.
词法范围让我们了解闭包是如何工作的，并且
Lexical scope gives us an understanding of how closure works, and
因此，闭包是理解模块模式的必要组件。
closure then is a necessary component to understand the module pattern.
在我们了解模块模式之前，
Before we look at what the module pattern is,
我们需要看看模块模式不是什么。
we need to look at what the module pattern is not.
这是一种非常常见的模式，一种常见的模式，其中有一组
This is an extremely common pattern, a common pattern where you have a set of
类似行为的函数和这些函数对其进行操作的一组数据。
behavior-like functions and a set of data that those functions operate on.
你想把它们收集到一个逻辑单元中，最简单的方法就是
And you wanna collect them together into some logical unit, the simplest way is to
只需创建一个对象，并将您的数据和函数直接放在该对象上。
just make an object and put your data and your functions directly on the object.
我想说这有个名字，非正式的，但是
I would say that this has a name, unofficially, but
这有一个名字作为模式，这是命名空间模式。
this had a name as a pattern, this is the namespace pattern.
取一组函数和数据并将它们放入对象内，
Taking a set of functions and data and putting them inside of an object,
将它们作为属性而不是变量，
putting them as properties instead of variables,
它有效地将它们收集到一个名称空间中。
it is effectively collecting them into a namespace.
不是真正的语言句法特性，但是
Not really a syntactic feature of the language, but
我们用对象创建名称空间是一种习惯用法。
it's an idiom that we make namespaces with objects.
多年来，这是一个非常普遍的模式。
And for years, this was an extremely common pattern.
这就是人们将功能收集在一起的方式。
This is how people collected functionality together.
这是一种原始的数据结构，如果你愿意的话。
This was sort of the primitive data structure, if you will.
这种特殊的模式没有什么问题。
Nothing wrong with this particular pattern.
我已经用过很多次了。
I've used it on many occasions.
您可能已经在自己的代码中看到了它。
You've probably seen it in your own code.
但我会告诉你，它绝对是，100%，绝对不是一个模块。
But i would tell you it is definitely, 100%, positively not a module.
它不是模块的原因是模块模式
And the reason it's not a module is that the module pattern
需要封装的概念。
requires the concept of encapsulation.
封装是一个听起来很奇特的CS单词。
Encapsulation is a fancy sounding CS word.
它真正的意思是隐藏数据和行为的想法。
All it really means is the idea of hiding data and behavior.
它真正的意思是，我不仅收集了它，
All it really means is, not only have I collected it together,
这就是名称空间创建的，但我需要一些隐藏的概念，
which is what the namespace creates, but I need some notion of hiding,
信息隐藏的一些想法，或对可见性的一些控制。
some idea for information hiding, or some control over visibility.
一个模块，一个模块的概念，就是有一些东西是公开的，
A module, the idea of a module, is that there are things that are public,
这是你的公共API，有些东西是私有的，
that's your public API, and there are things that are private,
这是外面没人能碰的东西。
that's things that nobody on the outside can touch.
有一种可见性的概念，即使唯一的可见性概念要么是公共的，要么是
There's an idea of visibility, even if the only visibility notion is either public or
私有，这仍然是封装思想的咒语。
private, that is still an incantation of the idea of encapsulation.
所以如果你想要一个模块，你必须有封装，
So if you wanna have a module, you gotta have encapsulation,
你必须有数据隐藏。
you gotta have data hiding.
在这里，我们可以清楚地看到属性和
And here, we can clearly see that the properties and
现有的函数是公共的，因此它不是一个模块。
functions that exist are public, therefore it's not a module.
所以我们可以采取同样的想法，在想法上分层，或者在技术上分层
So we can take this same idea and layer on the idea, or layer on the technique
信息隐藏的封装，我们一下子就把它变成了一个模块。
of encapsulation of information hiding, and we all of the sudden make it a module.
让我们看看这看起来是什么样子。
So let's look at what that looks like.
经典的模块模式，有时称为揭示模块
The classic module pattern, sometimes referred to as the revealing module
模式时，它封装数据，并使用闭包进行封装。
pattern, it encapsulates data and it does so with closure.
这才是关键。
That's key.
所以你不能有一个模块，如果你没有结束。
So you can't have a module, if you don't have closure.
这是不可能的好吗？
It's just not possible, okay?
即使是F6模块，我们将在概念上稍作讨论，
Even the F6 modules, which we will talk about in a little bit, conceptually,
我们需要把他们当做了结。
we need to think about them as closure.
模块模式，第一种被编码为经典的or
The module pattern, first sort of codified as the classic or
显示模块模式。
the revealing module pattern.
它是由道格·克劳福德-伊什于2001年编纂的，
It was codified by Doug Crawford-ish in 2001,
这就是它看起来的样子。
and this is kinda what it looks like.
它有两个组成部分。
It has two components to it.
第一，我们有一个外部封闭函数。
Number one, we have an outer enclosing function.
在这种情况下，这是一种生活，每个人都看到那里的生活了吗？
In this case, it's an IIFE, everybody see the IIFE there?
这是一种生活，而且
It's an IIFE, and
当我们把一个模块作为一个生命来运行时，这有点像说它是一个独生子。
when we run a module as an IIFE, that's kind of like saying it's a singleton.
因为我们知道生命运行一次
Since we know IIFEs run once and
然后他们完成了，这有点像独生子女。
then they're done, this is sort of like a singleton.
它运行一次，然后就完成了，除了只在空气引用的意义上完成，
It runs once, and then it's done, except done only in the air quote sense,
因为封闭会防止望远镜消失。
because the closure is gonna prevent that scope from going away.
第二个组成部分是我们有一个内部函数，
The second component then, is that we have an inner function,
在这种情况下，在第7行询问，这是在这些变量上闭合的，
in this case ask on line 7, that is closed over those variables,
在这种情况下，它在教师变量上关闭。
in this case, it is closed over the teacher variable.
因为它是在教师变量上关闭的，
Since it's closed over the teacher variable,
外部的车间对象，现在已经引用了该功能，
the workshop object on the outside, which has now reference to that function,
通过闭合来保存内部作用域。
is preserving that inner scope through closure.
问老师是封闭的，当我们说工作间的时候。问在外面，
Ask is closed over teacher, and when we say workshop.ask on the outside,
这个作用域没有被垃圾收集然后离开，那个作用域还在那里，
that's scope didn't get garbage collected and go away, that scope is still there,
这种状态仍然存在，这就是我们如何影响或
that state is still there, and that's how we effect or
创建模块模式，这是JavaScript中模块模式的习惯用法。
create the module pattern, the idiom of module pattern in JavaScript.
我们让我们的私人国家保持私人，我们在一个物体上暴露一些东西，
We keep our private state private, and we expose things on an object,
就像我在这里对公共API对象所做的那样。
like what I'm doing here with the public API object.
我只暴露Ask函数。
Is I'm exposing only the ask function.
但我可以有成百上千的其他私人功能，
But I could have hundreds of other functions that were private,
无法从外部访问。
that could not be accessed from the outside.
然而闭包函数可以整天访问它们，
And yet the closure functions can access them all day long,
如果他们想，因为结束了。
if they want to, because of closure.
所以我可以说Workshop.ask，但我不能说Workshop.教师。
So I can say workshop.ask, but I can't say workshop.teacher.
老师藏起来了。
Teacher is hidden.
卷起来。
Roll that.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这就是闭合无为。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's closure inaction.
这只是成百上千种可能的封闭性应用中的一种。
It's only one of hundreds of possible applications of closure.
但是我们不能这样做模块模式。
But we couldn't do the module pattern in this way.
我们不能影响这种信息隐藏的封装思想
We couldn't affect this idea of information hiding of encapsulation
没有结束。
without closure.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这里需要认识到的关键是
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: What's critical to recognize here is that this usage of
闭包实际上是对设计为改变状态的变量进行闭合
closure is actually closing over variables that are designed to change state
随着时间的推移。
over time.
这就是模块的全部目的，就是随着时间的推移跟踪状态。
That's the whole purpose of a module, is to track state over time.
事实上，我甚至会说，如果你有一个叫做模块的东西，
In fact, I'd go so far as to say, if you have a thing that you call a module,
它没有任何状态，或者更确切地说，
and it doesn't have any state, or rather,
它没有任何改变的状态，它不是一个模块。
it doesn't have any state that ever changes, it's not a module.
这只是一个过度设计的命名空间，好吗？
It's just an over-engineered namespace, okay?
模块的用途是您有一些关闭的状态，并且
The purpose of a module is that you have some state that you're closed over, and
您正在通过公开最小的公共API来控制对它的访问。
you are controlling access to it by exposing a minimal public API.
还记得最少接触特权的原则吗？
Remember that principle of least exposure privilege?
这就是在这里的行动。
That's in action here.
我们的意思是把所有东西都藏起来，
We're saying keep everything hidden,
除了最小限度地暴露在外面所必需的东西之外。
except minimally expose only what's necessary on the outside.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这就是这里的想法。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's the idea here.
最低限度地只暴露必要的东西。
Minimally expose only what's necessary.
这就是模块模式。
That's the module pattern.
现在，上一张幻灯片有一个模块生命，AKA，一个模块单例。
Now, the previous slide had a module IIFE, AKA, a module singleton.
但这不是制作模块的唯一方法。
But that's not the only way to make modules.
我们可以只制作可以多次调用的常规函数。
We can make just regular functions that can be called multiple times.
每次调用函数时，
And every time a function is called,
它将产生我们模块的一个新实例。
it's gonna produce a new instance of our module.
我们亲切地把它们称为工厂功能，好吗？
We lovingly refer to those as factory functions, okay?
这是车间模块工厂的功能。
This is a workshop module factory function.
我可以调用一次，就像我在第12行所做的那样，但我可以再调用一百次
I can call it once, like I do on line 12, but I could call it a hundred other times
并且有一百个其他单独的实例，它们都有自己的状态。
and have a hundred other separate instances that all have their own state.
它们都是分开的，它们不会相互混合。
They're all separate and they don't mix with each other.
简而言之，这就是模块模式。
And that is the module pattern in a nutshell.
我采取一些行为的想法，和
The idea that I take some behavior, and
行为操作的数据，并将其封装到数据结构中。
data that that behavior operates on, and encapsulate it into a data structure.
隐藏我不需要显示的内容，只公开最低限度的必要API。
Hide what I don't need to show, and expose only the minimal necessary API.
那是一个模块。
That's a module.
我认为模块模式肯定是最普遍的，
And I would argue that the module pattern is certainly the most prevalent,
并且可能是所有代码组织模式中最重要的。
and potentially the most important of all code organization patterns.
可能有80，90%的JavaScript曾经被写过
Probably 80, 90% of all JavaScript that's ever been written
使用了一些机制，比如模块模式作为它的代码组织模式。
has used some mechanism like the module pattern as it's code organization pattern.
这并不是说您没有其他模式，例如类，但是
That's not to say you don't have other patterns, like classes, for example, but
模块模式非常普遍和重要，并且
the module pattern is extremely prevalent and important, and
重要的是我们要了解它是如何工作的。
it's important that we understand how it works.
现在，让我们都承认这是一种语法攻击，这并不是真正的，
Now, let's all admit that this is sort of a syntactic hack, this is not really like,
你不会真的把这称为模块的第一类语言支持。
you wouldn't really call this first class language support for a module.
你可以称之为一种习语，一种我们确实使用的模式
You would call this an idiom, a pattern that we do using
以某种方式实现某些最终目标的工具。
the tools in a way that accomplishes some end goal.